Andy Stanier

andy.stanier@gmail.com www.andystanier.co.uk LinkedIn

Macclesfield, Cheshire

Andy Stanier has recently completed a master's degree in computer science. With a background in chemistry and 15 years' experience in the pharmaceutical industry, Andy is an intermediate level programmer in common languages and is eager to learn new techniques and languages as required.

Having being made redundant from the pharmaceutical industry several times, Andy decided to pursue his long-held interest in computer programming. Having undertaken several different online courses in programming and computer science as well as using books and YouTube videos to learn new skills, he enrolled in a computer science master's degree at the University of Hertfordshire, thus enabling him to gain a recognised formal qualification.

Skills

Andy has learned various different languages, techniques and software packages over the years, especially whilst studying for his master's degree. Some of these were learned prior to his formal study however the majority were learned during the last year. More details can be found in the Projects section.

Programming Languages			Techniques/Software
Java	HTML	CSS	Notepad++
JavaScript	JQuery	JSON	Sublime Text 2
C#	ASP.NET	SQL	MS Virtual Studio 2015
С	Python	XML	Command Line Interface
UML	Git	AJAX	BlueJ
C++	TypeScript	Angular.js	JIRA

Andy has also gained many transferable skills during 15 years working in the pharmaceutical industry:

- Problem Solving overcoming day-to-day issues with chemical synthesis.
- Research Skills consulting the literature for ideas and solutions.
- Planning designing the best synthetic route to a set of compounds.
- Tenacity working to produce compounds despite setbacks.
- Working to deadlines completing synthesis by a required testing date.
- Teamwork working in project teams of between 4 and 14 people.
- Independence working unaccompanied on sub-projects.

Work History

Aug 2015 - Sept 2016

Distance Learning Master's Student in Computer Science, University of Hertfordshire See Education section for more details.

May 2014 - Aug 2015

Synthetic Chemist at Molplex Pharmaceuticals, Alderley Park

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department. Molplex was a small biochemical start-up, whose aim was to use Artificial Intelligence to design new drugs for orphan diseases. Roles included: Establishing a working chemistry lab and office environment. Identifying and obtaining laboratory equipment and chemistry software tools at a reasonable price. Route design, synthesis and analysis of new chemical compounds for biochemical screening. Lab Safety officer including writing SOPs and safety policies.

Dec 2013 - May 2014

Looking for work - Job searching, CV writing and IT courses.

During this period, Andy attended Jobcentre run courses in CV writing, went to IT courses and applied for jobs in the pharmaceutical industry.

Jan 2011 - Dec 2013

Synthetic Organic Chemist for CK Science at Eisai, Hatfield

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department. Designed and synthesised libraries of compounds for screening. Prepared and delivered presentations to communicate progress and problems to colleagues at project and departmental meetings.

Aug 2008 - Jan 2011

Medicinal Chemist at AstraZeneca, Charnwood, Loughborough

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department. Designed and synthesised novel compounds within for biological screening against respiratory targets.

July 2001 - Aug 2008

Synthetic Chemist at AstraZeneca, Alderley Park, Macclesfield

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the research area. Worked within project teams to deliver compounds for biological screening in early and late stage discovery.

Education

Computer Science at University of Hertfordshire, UK

A distance learning Master's degree in Computer Science, studying the following:

- **Programming and Program Design** Learning **Java** language and Object Oriented Programming techniques using the **BlueJ** IDE. Assessment by exams and coursework; the final piece was a program, written from scratch, to a provided specification.
- Web Scripting and Application Development Learning about server-side website design using ASP.NET, C# and SQL. Created a website of user generated content.
- **Contemporary Practices in Information Technology** The ethics of information technology, assessed by researching and writing essays.
- Mobile Standards, Interfaces and Applications Learning about Ubiquitous computing, HCI, Wearable Computing, Context Awareness and using JavaScript, JSON and jQuery Mobile to generate a mobile website.

- **Secure Systems Programming** Exploring security problems with the **C** programming language and how to avoid them, plus learning about DDOS, BotNets, Worms and Viruses.
- Software Development Tools and Methods Ways to develop software, UML, XML, secure systems development. Assessment by essay and coursework drawing UML diagrams.
- Final Project in Computer Science A piece of research and practical work about Electronic Voting Systems, creating a desktop Java application and an HTML5 website for vote verification. Verson control was handled by Git software.

As well as these taught languages and skills, C++, TypeScript, Node.js, Angular.js and AJAX were investigated during private study.

Chemistry at University of York, UK

Chemistry with a Year in Industry, MChem with First Class Honours.

Three years of study and practical labs, coursework and exams. A fourth year was spent working in an industrial setting as a synthetic chemist in a drug discovery research department. Learning on the job and completing a written report and exams.

A Levels at Tytherington High School, Macclesfield

Four 'A' Levels in Mathematics (A), Chemistry (A), Physics (B) and General Studies (A).

Projects

Most of the projects here were produced as part of a Masters course and demonstrate some of the breadth of subjects studied.

- Oscars Mobile Website This is a website written as a piece of coursework for a
 mobile applications course which demonstrates the use of JQuery mobile. It
 contains a summary of all the films that have won 'Best Picture' Oscar since the first
 Academy Awards in 1928 to present day, and allows users to tick them off when
 they have seen them.
- Music Player This was a website written to practice using jQuery mobile in a simple website. This project is partially complete, however it demonstrates the use of jQuery mobile page structure and functions.
- Rodent Rooms This was an end of course project to show the use of ASP.NET and C# for a user generated content website, using an SQL database and server side user interface.
- **EVote** This was developed as part of the final project. It is a desktop Java application which simulates the creation and running of an election with electronic voting. The desktop program connects to an SQL database to collate votes.
- **Election Verification Tool** Also created for the final project, the website allows voters to verify that their vote has been correctly cast. The website uses ASP.NET, C# and SQL to create and control the content.
- Yahtzee Simulation A Python 3 program written to simulate the rolling of 5 dice simultaneously until five-of-a-kind is rolled, the process is repeated many times and the maximum, minimum and average number of rolls needed is recorded.

This CV is also available at www.andystanier.co.uk, where links to these projects can be found.